Shreyas Garga, Data Analyst

CONTACT

PHONE

703-986-6648

MAIL

garga.shreyas@gmail.com

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/shreyasgarga

GITHUB

https://github.com/sheygarga

TECHNOLOGY

PYTHON

SQL

NEURAL NETWORKS

JAVASCRIPT

MACHINE LEARNING/BIG DATA

ADVANCED EXCEL

JAVA

SKILLS

- DATA WRANGLING
- GRAPHING/CHARTING
- SOCIAL MEDIA MINING
- SQL/NoSQL APP BUILDING
- WEB SCRAPING
- WEB DEVELOPMENT
- GEO MAPPING
- INTERACTIVE VISUALIZATION
- STATISTICAL ANALYSIS WITH R
- TABLEAU/POWERBI

Summar

Driven data analyst with a Bachelor's in Neuroscience and experience in business and social analytics. Has created numerous automated and responsive data analytics applications and solutions to identify, analyze, and interpret trends and patterns. Excellent research and analytical skills. Gamer, Twitch streamer, guitarist, black belt in Tae Kwon Do, and a diehard sports fan.

Skillset

Python Pandas, Numpy, SciPy, MatPlotLib APIs, Tweepy, Vader, Seaborn, PySpark, Plotly,

Bokeh, PyTorch, NLTK, SpaCy, Gensim, Scrapy,

Database MySQL, MS SQL Server, MongoDB, SQLAlchemy, Flask

Web Javascript, Bootstrap, Angular, ChartJS, JQuery, D3, NodeJs, React, Leaflet, Carto, CSS
Big Data R, TensorFlow, Spark, Hadoop, NLP, MRJob, Keras, SKLearn, AWS, GCP AutoMl

Employment

Sevatec/United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Fairfax, VA

Data Analyst, Support, and Trainer

Aug 2019 - Current

Technologies: Python, R, SQL, Jupyter, SMART/OBIEE, SAS, SAS Viya, DataBricks, Tableau, Excel **Responsibilities:**

- Design and develop an automated application approval system for faster and more efficient adjudication of immigration cases.
- Responsible for data cleaning and data analysis using LASSO Regression, correlation matrices, and stepwise subsets to build predictive models for machine learning.
- Utilized K-means clustering to find correlations between cases, decision trees based on agents'
 protocols for case evaluation, and neural networks to process the numerous variables and factors.
- Designed data dashboards using a variety of data visualizers to help analyze trends and tendencies.

Administrative Office of the US Courts

Washington DC

Lead Data Analyst - IT Security

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019

Technologies: MySQL, Excel, Tableau, Tableau Prep, d3, PlotLy, and Numpy **Responsibilities:**

- Design and create dynamic and interactive Excel and Tableau Dashboards for the executives to help analyze threats, identify trends and make strategic decisions.
- Import Security Threats data from the judiciary units across the country into MySQL and write Python scripts to convert data into intelligent information.
- Present findings to the management and prepare reports for the executives to present in Federal and State Level regulatory meetings.
- Responsible for prompt and accurate analysis to help ensure cybersecurity for the judiciary.

vyuct Herndon, VA

Developer and Data Analyst

Alyst May 2018 – Oct 2018

Project: Object Detection

Technologies: COCO, RCNN, Google Cloud Platform, TensorFlow, Python

Responsibilities:

- Set-up environments on Google Cloud Platform to enable development and testing.
- Develop Python Scripts to convert datasets to TFRecords
- Integrate pre-trained COCO Datasets for Transfer Learning.
- Configured pipeline to tune model and training parameters.

Project: Skills Gap Analysis

Technologies: Neo4j, Python, NLP

Responsibilities:

- Develop Python Libraries for dependency parsing using NLP
- Write scripts to clean and process dependency parsing results and load to Graph database.
- Customize properties of nodes and relations to draw inference and make recommendations.

Project: Sentiment Analysis

Technologies: Twitter, Python, Tweepy, Pandas, NumPy, TensorFlow, Keras

Responsibilities:

- Extracted training data and relevant tweets using Pandas, NumPy, and Tweepy.
- Trained the model using TensorFlow and Keras
- Transformed the script to accept inputs from the company website for trial usage

Education

George Washington University: Data Analyst/Data Visualization Certificate

George Mason University: BS in Neuroscience Aug 2013- Dec 2017